<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>serial experiments lento</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00+09:00</updated><entry><title>Strict Symmetry in Buddhism Art</title><link href="/3-strict_symmetry_in_buddhism_art.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00+09:00</updated><author><name>lento</name></author><id>tag:None,2024-11-17:/3-strict_symmetry_in_buddhism_art.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I visited &lt;a href="https://asianart.org/"&gt;Asian Art Museum&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco on November 2, 2024. My primary reason for going was to explore how Asian art, especially Japanese art, is perceived in US as a Japanese person. In addition to that, I wanted to view Chinese paintings, as I had recently developed …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I visited &lt;a href="https://asianart.org/"&gt;Asian Art Museum&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco on November 2, 2024. My primary reason for going was to explore how Asian art, especially Japanese art, is perceived in US as a Japanese person. In addition to that, I wanted to view Chinese paintings, as I had recently developed an interest in Chinese art. My visit was fulfilling. Comprehensive explanations of the arts seem to captivate visitors. Also, I was totally inspired by the magnificent Chinese paintings, which offered profound insights from both local and global perspective. However, the article is not about those aspects; It is about one Buddhist sculpture that captivated my attention to pause and reflect. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scenes of the Life of Buddha&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stone sculpture, titled &lt;a href="https://searchcollection.asianart.org/objects/12303/scenes-of-the-life-of-the-buddha"&gt;"Scenes of the Life of Buddha"&lt;/a&gt;, was discovered in India and dates back to between 1000 and 1200 CE. As the title indicates, various scenes from the life of Buddha are intricately curved into the stone. Despite its astonishingly small size (16.5 cm x W. 12.7 cm x D. 5.1 cm), each scene is crafted with extraordinary precision. Examining the sculpture reveals three horizontal lines with a relatively larger central Buddha representing his victory over Mara. Each row has four representations of Buddha, and rightmost and leftmost ones mean memorable scenes. According to the &lt;a href="https://about.asianart.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2020/06/SA02_placard-masterpiece-sm.pdf"&gt;museum document&lt;/a&gt;, each scene can be summarized in the following table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Order of line from above&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Leftmost scene&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Rightmost scene&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1st&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Buddha's descent from Indra's Heaven&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Buddha taming an enraged elephant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2nd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Buddha's preaching&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No descriptions. It may be different scene from the leftmost scene because the pedestal is different.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3rd&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Buddha accepting an offering from a monkey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Buddha's birth&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every scene has to be distinct. Nevertheless, scenes within the same line are so similar that they can be difficult to differentiate. The scenes in the 3rd row are relatively easier to distinguish due to their pronounced poses. In contrast, the scenes in the 2nd line appear nearly identical, though the meaning of the rightmost scene remains unclear. Similarly, the scenes in the 1st line also resemble each other, though some parts are damaged. 
Turning to another sculpture, titled &lt;a href="https://searchcollection.asianart.org/objects/11146/seated-crowned-buddha-with-four-scenes-of-his-life"&gt;"Seated crowned Buddha with four scenes of his life"&lt;/a&gt;, which was also found in India and dates back to 1100 and 1200 CE, there are two rows framing the central Buddha. The upper line depicts two scenes: the Buddha's descent from Indra's Heaven and the Buddha taming an enraged elephant. They are so similar that they are nearly indistinguishable unless one notices the small elephant in the latter. Additionally, I spotted another sculpture with identical poses, differing only in the design of the pedestal. The strict symmetry, which seems to prioritize aesthetic balance over narrative clarity, struck me as peculiar. Of course, the emphasis on symmetry various depending on the region or era where the sculptures are created. However, the overall impression of viewing the collection of Buddhist art from India symmetry seems to have been a significant focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Scenes of the Life of Christ&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the sculpture depicting scenes of life of a significant figure, many examples portray the life of Christ. One such piece is the &lt;a href="https://art.thewalters.org/detail/31438/diptych-leaf-with-scenes-from-the-passion-of-christ/"&gt;"Diptych Leaf with Scenes from the Passion of Christ"&lt;/a&gt;made of ivory found in France dating back to 1250-1270. Despite its small size (32.6 x 13 x 0.8 cm), it also captures scenes ranging from Temptation of Judas to Entombment, with each scene clearly distinguishable. Another example is the &lt;a href="https://www.metmuseum.org/art/collection/search/468339"&gt;"Diptych with Scenes from the Passion of Jesus"&lt;/a&gt; found in France dating back to 1350s. The piece features six scenes that are distinct enough to be easily recognized. While the arches framing each scene maintain symmetric, the entire symmetry is less rigid compared to that of Buddhist sculptures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hypothesis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So is strict symmetry or loose symmetry a key characteristic in defining the direction of India Buddhism art or Christian art? Answering the question is challenging and requires comprehensive investigation of these arts across various regions and time periods. The following is my "rough" hypothesis to start my exploration. I guess that the strict symmetry serves as the strong condition in the creation of arts. When the symmetry becomes highly pronounced, it often diminishes the realistic detail, transforming the artwork into a symbol or icon. The Buddhist sculptures discussed above likely are not the educational contents but the spiritual icons for the followers. Conversely, the asymmetry leads to more realistic and detailed depictions, enhancing the ability to convey specific narratives. The characteristic is evident in Christian art, where paintings and sculptures would be visual foundations to illustrate the stories of the New Testament. The contrast between symmetry and asymmetry would represent the most fundamental differences when comparing the artistic traditions of Buddhism and Christianity. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="art"></category><category term="art"></category></entry><entry><title>Henri Matisse "Woman with a hat"</title><link href="/2-woman_with_a_hat.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-22T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00+09:00</updated><author><name>lento</name></author><id>tag:None,2024-01-22:/2-woman_with_a_hat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2023, I visited &lt;a href="https://www.sfmoma.org/"&gt;San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (SFMOFA)&lt;/a&gt;. I encountered a group of elementary school students who had just finished their tour when I just entered the museum. As I ascended to the second stair, I found myself imagining what the students might …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2023, I visited &lt;a href="https://www.sfmoma.org/"&gt;San Francisco Museum of Modern Art (SFMOFA)&lt;/a&gt;. I encountered a group of elementary school students who had just finished their tour when I just entered the museum. As I ascended to the second stair, I found myself imagining what the students might have seen and thought. My primary goal for the visit was to view "Woman with a hat" by Henri Matisse, which is one piece of the SFMOMA collection. I was thrilled to view the paining that locates alongside an outstanding array of the modern art paintings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Exhibition at Tokyo Metropolitan Art Museum&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My impetus to see the painting traces back to May 2023. I went to Tokyo Metropolitan Art Museum to see &lt;a href="https://www.tobikan.jp/en/exhibition/2023_matisse.html"&gt;the special exhibition featuring Matisse&lt;/a&gt; during the trip to Japan. The exhibition captivated me for two main reasons. First, it was a rare opportunitie to see so many Matisse's works in one place, which is about 150 paintings from the Centre Pompidou in Paris. Second, I had longed for seeing &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luxe,_Calme_et_Volupt%C3%A9"&gt;"Luxe, Calme et Volupté"&lt;/a&gt; in person, captivated by an audacious distribution of colors, and the painting came to the exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Title of the exhibition" src="/images/2_path_to_the_color.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exhibition offered a meaningful journey through a Matisse's life as an artist, from early Realism paintings to the late-life masterpiece, the Chapel of the Rosary. While Matisse is often celebrated as a pioneer of Fauvism and a magician of color, this exhibit showed that his focal point extended byyond color to include a deep exploration of form. For example, &lt;a href="https://www.nortonsimon.org/art/detail/PH.1989.1.3a-d"&gt;"The Back Ⅰ-Ⅳ"&lt;/a&gt; series representing a woman's back, reveals a trajectory from detailed contours to nearly abstract vertical lines, implying his quest to distill from itself. I sensed that Matisse might have been continually asking himself, "What is the minimum composition of the object in terms of colors and shapes?". This question would culminate in his cutouts and the chapel with their astonishing simplicity, though a choice would be partly influenced by his physical challenges in his later life. As a machine learning researcher specializing in representation learning, I have been fasciated by the minimal composition of objects. Discovering a possible kinship between Matisse's artistic inquiry and my own research interest was unexpectedly gratifying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the exhibition featured few paintings from Matisse's Fauvist period. As I understand that Fauvism was only a brief phase in his long artistic journey, the observation just reflects my personal preference for that period. Curious to know where his famous Fauvist works, "Woman with a hat" and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Green_Stripe"&gt;"Portrait of Madame Matisse (The green line)"&lt;/a&gt; are located, I found that the latter locates in Statens Museum for Kunst, while the former is it SFMOMA. That is why I have decided to visit SFMOMA to see the painting in person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Woman with a hat&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Woman with a hat" src="/images/1_woman_with_a_hat.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sfmoma.org/artwork/91.161/"&gt;"Woman with a hat"&lt;/a&gt; represents a rebellion of color. Almost all the colors here are detached from reality; for instance, although Matisse's wife wore a black dress in real life, the painting presents it in a strikingly different color, as noted in the caption. I would like not to touch the origin of Fauvism as it has been discussed widely, but viewing "Luxe, Calme et Volupté" in Japan has reinforced my idea that Pointillism would have given a influence to Fauvism. Pointillist artists used complementary (often unrealistic) colors in tiny dots to enhance vibrancy. While Seurat, the founder of Pointillism, &lt;a href="https://www.artic.edu/artworks/27992/a-sunday-on-la-grande-jatte-1884"&gt;had put millions of tiny dots following the principle&lt;/a&gt;, later artists like Signac and Delaunay gradually &lt;a href="https://collection.nmwa.go.jp/en/P.1987-0003.html"&gt;increased the size of these dots and expanded their use of non-realistic colors&lt;/a&gt;. The evaluation may have sparked the question among artists: "Why limit color to what the object actually has?", paving the way for Fauvism. Given the transition and the Pointillism's influence on artists like Delaunay, Van Gogh, and Kandinsky, not only Matisse had the possibility to initiate Fauvism. However, Matisse alone achieved the unique balance of audacious color and beauty that defines the style. Hence, "Woman with a hat" stands as a monumental work marking the advent of Fauvism.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="art"></category><category term="art"></category></entry><entry><title>AwesomeAnimeResearch: Past, Present, and Future</title><link href="/1-awesomeanimeresearch.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-11-24T00:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2022-11-24T00:00:00+09:00</updated><author><name>lento</name></author><id>tag:None,2022-11-24:/1-awesomeanimeresearch.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have created and managed a repository, named &lt;a href="https://github.com/SerialLain3170/AwesomeAnimeResearch"&gt;AwesomeAnimeResearch&lt;/a&gt; for more than two years (the first commit was at 04/27/2020). Thanks to contributors and issue builders, we have collected more than 250 papers related to anime, illustration, and comic. I would like to explain motivation to create …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have created and managed a repository, named &lt;a href="https://github.com/SerialLain3170/AwesomeAnimeResearch"&gt;AwesomeAnimeResearch&lt;/a&gt; for more than two years (the first commit was at 04/27/2020). Thanks to contributors and issue builders, we have collected more than 250 papers related to anime, illustration, and comic. I would like to explain motivation to create the repository, design, present challenges, and future plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until I created the repository, I used to take a look at &lt;a href="https://github.com/shubhampachori12110095/DeepLearningAnimePapers"&gt;DeepLearningAnimePapers&lt;/a&gt; to investigate papers related to anime. Since it had stopped updates in 2018, I had possessed a desire to create awesome-list for anime papers that contains a massive and exciting collection. Therefore, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/NieA7_3170/status/1258700433356283910?s=20&amp;amp;t=PrGYp5veSVDrUamtQqjMCg"&gt;I started to manage AwesomeAnimeResearch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the first place, what is the definition of "papers related to anime, illustration, and comic"? I have defined it as the published or preprint papers that explicitly include applications for these fields. For example, if the paper is about image generation and includes the generated figures of not only human faces but also anime characters, the paper clearly shows potentials for anime applications. Of course, since the definition is from all my perspectives, I am willing to discuss the appropriate definition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are 2 categories of resources in AwesomeAnimeResearch: paper and project. Papers are the papers in accordance with the definition that I stated. Projects are not the papers but they are tech reports or github repositories that have contributed to promoting machine learning research related to anime (e.g. &lt;a href="https://make.girls.moe/#/"&gt;makegirlsmoe&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://github.com/lllyasviel/style2paints"&gt;style2paints&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have set 21 categories like below based on my perspective, and four categories have their own subcategories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;- Dataset
- Image Generation
  |- Generation
  |- Few-shot
  |- Interpretability
  |- Montage
- Image-to-Image Translation
  |- Face2anime
  |- Selfie2anime
  |- Photo2anime
  |- Sketch2anime
  |- Photo2manga
  |- Anime2costume
  |- Style transfer
  |- Author style transfer
- Automatic Line Art Colorization
  |- NoHint
  |- Atari
  |- Reference
  |- Tag
  |- Video
- Automatic Character Lighting
- Automatic Illustration Editing
- Automatic Sketch Editing
- Automatic Animation Inbetweening
- Automatic Image Enhancement
- Character Animating
- Manga Application
  |- Generation
  |- Restoration
  |- Inpainting
  |- Text detection
  |- Landmark detection
  |- Segmentation
  |- Translation
  |- Depth estimation
  |- Vectorization
  |- Re-identification
- Representation Learning
- Pose Estimation
- Image Retrieval
- Visual Correspondence
- Character Recognition
- 3D Character Creation
- Robotics
- Speech Synthesis
- Adult Content Detection
- Survey
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When it comes to the papers, each record has three or four fields depending on the existence of subcategories.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Subcategory&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;category&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;does&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;have&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;subcategories&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;field&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;does&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;exist&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;required&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;link&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Conference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;abbreviated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;conference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;including&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;year&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;optional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Webpages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;describing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;aside&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;published&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;e&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="nv"&gt;g&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;repository&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;specific&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;webpage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;Multiple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;sources&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;OK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As for the projects, each record has the link and the name of the project. If the project is about the tech report and the webpage, the title is treated as the name. If the project is about the github repository, a combination of the username and the name of the repository corresponds to the name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Present Challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diversity&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two aspects about the diversity: number of papers and uniqueness.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of papers: I have noticed that the current version of AwesomeAnimeResearch lacks papers among several categories. Some categories include abundant papers, and others do not. I have to admit that the lack comes from my interests. Although several issue builders and contributers have mitigated the problem, there seems still be imbalanced with respect to the number of papers. Moreover, the categorization that I showed in the design section is not expected for researchers working on speech processing and natural language processing because the current categories lack papers related to the areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uniqueness: Papers among some categories would be overabundant because several pairs of the papers in one category mostly resemble each other. The truncation would be imperative to enable users to access to the desired paper faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completeness&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of dead links for the paper and blanks in the conference name exist. Especially as for the former problem, it significantly decreases the accessibility of users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will continue to add papers and projects to the repository via a search in reddit and google scholar. I also always accept issues and PR from others. Especially the latter leads to mitigating the problems of diversity. On the other hand, I am thinking about creating the script to search papers related to each category. This script would not only solve the problem of dead links and blanks but also enhance the objectiveness in searching the papers. If you have questions, corrections, or suggestions, I am willing to welcome and discuss them via Github Issue.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="cs"></category><category term="cs"></category></entry></feed>